这垃圾谁选的?
who picked this dump?
你自己提议的
you suggested it.
我提议你研究一下
I suggestedyou look into it.
抱歉 网上评论...
Sorry.Theabconline reviews--
显然是他们自己的市场部呆子们写的
were obviously writtenby some geekabcin their own marketingdepartment.
下次找个靠谱的
Next time,call someone you know.
别老指望电脑为你完成工作
Stop relying on a computerabcto do your job for you.
Brightsize一案abc两年内八起性骚扰事件
Brightsize apparel-- eight sexualabcharassment suitsin two years.
- 谁提出开会的?abc- 他们
- Who asked for the meeting?abc- They did.
我是Patty Michenerabc女性优势基金会主席
patty michener, presidentabcof women's majority.
你们还真需要我!
And wow-- doabcyou guys need me!
九个清一色男性
Nine men.
至少也让个女记录员什么的加入进来
No one thoughtit might be a goodabcidea to put a suit on one of the gals
逢场作戏表示下你们还在乎嘛
from the steno pool to makeabcit look likeyou give a damn?
我们已经把提升妇女abc当成重中之重了 但--
We've made it a prioritytoabcpromote more women, but--
现在你们有我在这里了abc是件好事
well, from now on you have meabcstanding beside you, which is good.
因为你们的问题是全国性问题
Because your problemabcis a national problem.
无意冒犯 Michener小姐
with all due respect, miss michener,
我觉得几个不相关的事件abc很难算是全国性问题
I'd hardly call a few isolatedabcincidents a national problem.
十个受害者中六个根本没有报案被骚扰
six out of ten victimsabcnever even report harassment.
这不只是八个女性的事情
This is bigger than just eight women.
那还是只有20个
That still only means 20.
难道还不够吗?
Not enough for you?
你们公司的政策允许你摸几个屁股?
How many asses does yourabccorporate policy allow you to grab?
告诉你们该怎么做吧
Tell you what you're gonna do.
该和解赔钱的就赔钱
You're gonna settle withabcanyoneyou haven't settled with.
任何被指有性骚扰的员工都要开除
You're gonna fire anyabcmanwho's even been accused.
帮帮我 我弄不走它们
Somebody help me! Pleaseabchelp me. I can't get 'em off!
来人救救我 来人啊
Please help me! Help me, please!abcSomebody help me! Get 'em off.
你们是打算叫救护车abc还是就这么一直看着?
You gonna call an ambulance, or areabcyou just gonnasit there and stare?
拜托救救我!
Help me, please!
Wilson回来了 你要不要去...
Wilson'sabcback.You gonna--
他一走就是两个月
he's been gone two months.
等我屠了这个戴无边帽穿紧身裤的人abc再去也不迟
He can wait till I finish slaying aabcguy in a skullcap and a pair of tights.
玩你从儿科病房偷来的游戏?
On a video game you stoleabcfrom the pediatric ward?
根据律师意见abc我行使第五修正案沉默权…
On advice of counsel, I assert myabcprivilege pursuant to the fifth.
你上回和他说话是什么时候?
When was the lastabctime you talked to him?
我想是在...
Uh, I think it was after...
他女朋友什么时候死的来着?
when did his girlfriend die?
他想要一个人静一静
He wanted time alone.
我有想过做个讨厌烦人精的
I considered being aabchorrendous pain in the ass,
但那不就抢了你的风头
but I didn't want to tread on your turf.
有新案例了
We got a case.
下次一定要记得关上百叶窗
I've gotta remember to close the blinds.
女性优势基金会的patty michener打来abc她是女权组织的…
Just got a call from patty michener fromabcwomen's majority, the women's rights--
我们知道她是谁
we know who she is.
我还和她约会过
I dated her.
不是真正的那种约会
Well, not really dated her.
算是因为长着那玩意就变相强奸了她
More metaphorically rapedabcher by having a penis.
你也是
You did too.
她的助手突然失常
Her assistant flipped out.
在一屋子的商务人士面前abc自己扒光衣服
Ripped off her clothes in frontabcof a room full of businessmen.
她要不是因为压力崩溃了abc就是突然意识到...
Well, either she cracked under theabcwhip, or she started to realize that
进化赋予她的意义abc不是阉割男人而是激发他们
her evolutionary purpose is toabcarouse men, not to castrate them.
送她去精神病医师那
Send her to psychiatric.
贫血症 心动过缓慢和腹痛abc可不是精神病症状
Anemia, bradycardia, and abdominalabcpain aren't psychiatric symptoms.
那就是后面那个原因啦
Then it's the latter.
送她到我家来吧
Send her to my apartment.
我会把案例给Segal医生
I'll give it to segal.
House真正想接病例了 你却不同意?
House actually wants aabccase, and you're saying no?
House有更重要的事情要做
House has more important things to do.
抱歉 帮不了你了
Sorry, can't help you.
要去除你那湿疣必须找专家
You need a specialist toabcremove those kind of warts.
要找对那特殊部位比较了解的专家
Preferably one withabcexperience spelunking.
幻觉 可能的失忆
Hallucinations, possible memory loss.
测试显示她贫血 心率过缓abc而且坚定地不剃腋毛
Tests show anemia, slow heart rate, andabca stubborn refusal to shave her pits.
你见过wilson没?
Have you seen wilson?
没有 但病人坐飞机倒很频繁
Nope. But I have seen theabcpatient's frequent flyer balance.
东欧 亚洲 第三世界国家abc有时一天内还不止一次
Eastern europe, asia, third-worldabccountries. Sometimes more than one a day.
没有发烧 说明不是热带地区疾病
No fever means it'sabcnot a tropical disease.
也许和她去的地方没关系abc问题在她的工作时间
If it's not where she went,abcmaybe it's the work hours.
可能是滥用安菲他命
Could be amphetamine abuse.
压力大了就像吃薄荷糖一样乱吃
She's probably poppingabcthem like breath mints.
你还没去过他的办公室?
You haven't been by his office?
产生蚂蚁爬遍全身的幻觉的abc又不是Wilson
Is wilson hallucinating antsabccrawling all over him too?
毒性测试的结果abc比她拒不擦拭的窗户更干净
Tox screen's cleaner thanabcthe windows she won't do.
她的工作让她长期奔波 可能天天靠吃abc飞机上发的花生米和无糖苏打水
Her job keeps her constantly on the road, probablyabcliving off of airline peanuts and diet soda.
严重缺乏维生素B12可能导致上述症状
Severe b12 deficiency couldabccause all her symptoms.
为何大家都立马认为abc事业有成的女性是因事业有成而生病的?
Why is everyone leaping to conclude a strongabccareer woman's been made sick by her strong career?
不是维生素B12缺乏 是胰腺里的胰岛瘤
It's not b12, it's anabcinsulinoma in her pancreas.
导致她血糖过低
It's making her hypoglycemic.
好 终于大家都知道了
Great. Now everyone knows.
你知道病人有癌症?
You knew the patient had cancer?
她刚刚不就是那个意思吗?
Is that what she said?
我觉得她的意思是 我突然开始abc不分青红皂白地为病人的繁荣事业辩护
I thought she said, "I am suddenly andabcirrationally defending "the patient's strong career,
虽然她不过也只是个美其名的小人物
"even though in realityabc"she's just a glorified grunt?
因为我在努力说服自己abc像我这样除了工作没有生活是可以的
"Because I'm trying to convince myself that it'sabcokay "not to have a life because I don't have a life.
因为我被检查出亨廷顿跳舞症abc只剩一半寿命了
"Because I was tested for huntington's,abcand my life span's been cut in half."
我等了她两个月说这个了
Been waiting two monthsabcfor her to say that.
幻觉 贫血 心动过缓--
Hallucinations,abcanemia, bradycardia--
白细胞核非正常多叶abc证明Taub是对的
hypersegmented polysabcsays that taub's right.
给她多多的维生素B12
Pump her full of b12.
看看事业有成的女性是怎么被abc被有成的事业弄病的
See how a strong career woman'sabcbeen made sick by her strong career.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
可能会很多年以后才有症状
Could be yearsbeforeabcyou see any symptoms.
你怎么不告诉我们?
Why wouldn't you tell us?
我没有亨廷顿跳舞症
I don't have huntington'S.
你骗我们...
Are you lying to us...
是因为觉得不关我们的事?
because it's noneof our business?
如果不关你们的事abc我就不需回答这些了
If it's noneof your business, then Iabcshouldn't haveto answer these questions.
我本也不需要abc都是因为house不想回答关于wilson的问题
And I wouldn't have to, except houseabcdoesn't want toanswer questions about wilson.
就把自己的问题转移到我这里
He's deflectinghis own problems onto me.
你现在是在转移话题吗
Are you deflecting now?
要去给病人用维生素B12abc并且上我的人生大课了
Time for a b12abccocktailand my life lesson.
不 Patty会参加听证会
No, patty will dothe hearing.
她要当第一证人 以便...
She just needs to betheabcleadoff witness so--
好的 我今天就搞定
okay, I'll lock it down today.
你得回床上去
I need you back in bed.
我老板要去北京出趟大差
My boss hasa big beijing trip.
我已经准备了好几个月
I've been planning itfor months.
只是有点过劳加脱水--
I was just tiredandabcdehydrated and--
少睡了几个觉abc就会重击双腿假想蚂蚁大军?
ye, whenever I losesome shut-eye, I poundabcmy legs, clawingat imaginary ant colonies.
你有严重的维生素B12缺乏症abc回床上去
You have a severeb12abcdeficiency. Get back in bed.
我相信你老板没有你几天也能行
I'm sure your boss canabcdowithout you for a few days.
不是她 是为了我
It's not about her. It's about me.
我想去那儿 我想起作用
I want to be there. I want to matter.
是啊 没了你abc他们很难拿捏她的衣服浆洗程度
Yeah, I mean,without you, who knows howabcmuch starch they'd put in her shirts?
抱歉 我相信你的老板一定很依赖你
I'm sorry, I'm sureyourabcboss depends on you for--
我得起来
I need to get up.
- 不 你得好好卧床abc- 拜托 便盆在哪里?
- No, you need to stayin bed.abc- Please, where's a bed pan?
哦 天啊 很抱歉
Oh, my god, I'm sorry.
我刚刚好像排便了
I just-- I just hadabca bowel movement.
没事的 维生素b12缺乏abc有可能造成突然的...
It's okay, b12abcdeficiencycan cause sudden--
这不是排便
that's not a bowel movement.
我的病人...
My patient...
还在为女权主义奋战abc但战斗已经结束了
is still fightingin the feministabctrenches, but the war is over.
从前的荡妇变成了现在的女强人
Yesterday's slutsareabctoday's empowered women.
现在的荡妇成了名人abc这还真是进步
Today's sluts are celebrities.Ifabcthat isn't progress--
我要走了
I'm leaving.
什么 你又要消失两个月?
What, are you gonnaabctakeanother two months?
你真是趁着丧亲多占便宜啊
Boy, you're really milkingabcthisbereavement thing, aren't you?
我是说 很好啊abc想花多久都可以
I mean, good for you.abcTake all the time you need.
我要辞职了
I'm resigning.
可能离开新泽西 还不确定
Maybe moving out of newabcjersey. I don't know yet.
这个反应可以理解
Okay. That's an understandablereaction.
这不是反应 是决定
It's not a reaction. It's a decision.
我在写给Cuddy的辞职信
I'm writing cuddymyabcresignation right now.
我只是这周回来abc料理完临床和行政上的后事
I'm just back for the weekto wrap upabcmy clinical andadministrative duties.
你自己最清楚 这是丧亲后的典型表现abc觉得自己改变一下…
You of all people should know,this isabcbereavement 101.You think thata change of venue--
多谢你帮我省了几十年的心理治疗
well, that spares meabcdecadesof psychoanalysis.
我不是说你现在不痛苦
I'm not sayingyou're not in pain.
你是说我的痛苦没新意？
You're sayingmy pain's a cliche.
- 我是说痛苦是会消磨掉的abc- 你的痛苦消磨掉了吗?
- I'm saying that pain fades.abc- Did yours?
生理疼痛不算
Physical pain is different.
我宁愿切掉一条腿
I'd rather have my legchopped off.
- 你才不知道 你没体会过…abc- 你也没体会过我的痛
- You don't know that 'cause youabchaven't felt-- - neither have you.
- 抱歉 病人直肠出血abc- 我很忙
- Sorry--patient's gotaabcrectal bleed. - Busy.
- 我们需要你abc- 事实上正如你看到的 我不忙
- We need you to-- - actually,abcas you can see,I'm not busy.
刚才只是委婉地叫你马上出去
It's just a euphemismforabc"get the hell out of here."
你是被悲痛冲昏了头
This is your grieftalking.
像教科书里说的一样
And, yeah, it isa bit textbook.
你把全部家当捐给教会之前--
So before you give awayall yourabcpossessions to the salvation army--
我女朋友死了
my girlfriend's dead.
很高兴你读过那本教科书abc我没有
I'm glad you've readthatabcbook before. I haven'T.
我要去给Olan医生简报一下abc让他接手的病例
I'm late to meetdr. Olan to briefabchim on the casesI'm handing over.
再见
Bye.
House不肯在病人身上花两秒钟abc你们不担心吗?
It doesn't bother youthat house wouldn't takeabcjust two secondsto talk about the patient?
Wilson那事够他受的
Wilson's dealingwith a lot.
但病人可能会丧命
And our patientmay be dying.
她后方出血 我们看看就是了
she was bleeding out her rear.abcWe're looking up her rear.
你认为我们需要House来教这个吗?
You think we neededhouse'sabcexpertise to set us on this course?
她的心跳很慢 出血本该加快的
Her heart rate's slow--bleedshouldabchave made it faster.
我们找到出血部位再说
And it can wait till afterweabcknow where it came from,
也在他料理完个人私事再说
and after he's doneabcdealingwith personal issues.
是吗 这里是这个规矩吗?
Yeah? That the wayit works around here?
有个人私事就可以不干活?
We get cut slack whileabcwe dealwith personal sues?
你不是老大
You're not the boss.
老大定规矩 老大忽略规矩
Boss gets to maketheabcrules.Boss gets to ignore--
她的出血…没来由
she's bleeding from... nowhere.
- 你们做了内窥镜？abc- 还有结肠镜检查
- You did an endoscopy?abc- And a colonoscopy.
- CT扫描?abc- 已经预定了
- Ct scan?abc- Ordered.
但不会有什么是内窥镜显示不出来的
But it shouldn't showabcanythingthe endoscopy didn'T.
我们不能做CT扫描
We can't do a ct scan.
为什么?
Why not?
我们不需要CT扫描 也不需要House
We don't need a ct scan.abcWe don't need house.
别坏笑了好好说话
Stop grinning and talk.
一项常规术前检查结果是阳性
One of the routineabcpre-proceduretests was positive.
哪项?
Which one?
那项能够解释激素失调
The one that,if it's positive,abcwould explaina hormone imbalance
并影响心跳和血流的
that could screw withabcheart rateand blood flow.
我猜她确实工作之余确实还有生活
Guess she does have aabclifebeyond her career.
我怀孕了?
I'm pregnant?
需要我给孩子父亲打个电话告诉他吗?
You want me to call theabcfatherand let him know?
你先做个DNA鉴定让我知道孩子爸是谁吧
Soon as you dosome dnaabctesting, let me know.
工作这么忙 维持固定感情一定很难…
Must be hard to haveaabcreal relationship when--
你是在为我开脱吗?
are you making excusesfor me?
我只是说这可以理解
I'm just sayingit's understandable.
只有需要解释的时候才谈得上理解
You only haveto understandabcsomething if it needs an explanation.
我有生理需要 我满足了需要abc这就解释了一切
I have needs. I met myabcneeds. End of explanation.
你最近是什么时候 有需要的?
How recently were you... needy?
至少两到三个月了
Oh, it's been two orabcthree months, at least.
怎么了?
What? What is it?
什么都没有
Nothing.
告诉我吧
Tell me.
就是什么都没有
It's actually nothing.
超声显示没有一点胎儿痕迹
The ultrasound shows noabctraceof a baby at all.
检查阳性 却没有怀孕
Positive pregnancy test, no pregnancy.
维生素B12缺乏已纠正 但她心率却更慢了
B12 deficit rectified, butherabcheart's slowing even more.
而且出血会导致她心率加快
And a bleed should speedher heart rate.
House 这是你大爱的病例
House, this isthe kind of case you love.
矛盾重重 左右不定
Contradictions piling upleft and right.
两项假阳性妊娠试验abc心动过缓 下消化道出血 说
Two false positivepregnancy tests,abcbradycardia,lower G.I.Bleed. Go.
绒毛膜癌 可以导致孕激素上升
Choriocarcinoma--would'vetriggeredabcpregnancy hormones.
也会在超声上显示
Also would have shownon a sonogram.
a免疫球蛋白缺乏
immunoglobulin "a" deficiency.
尿潜血阴性
No urinary bleed.
如果她注射过β-HCG(绒毛膜促性腺素)abc会产生交叉反应以导致...
If she's hadbeta hcg injections,abcthey can cross-react with...
继续
keep going.
你就是个白痴
You're being an idiot.
你非要毁了你的事业是吧
You're gonna blow up your career.
六个月之前你才开始忘了sienna向amber靠拢
And six months from now,when you'veabcmoved on from amber to burnt sienna,
你会流落到小地方的abc移动肿瘤诊疗车里
you're gonna be stuckin a mobileabconcology truck in pewaukee, wisconsin.
我需要个流程图来解释abc你怎么总是这么冷酷无情
I'd need a flow chartto explain all the waysabcin which that wasridiculously insensitive.
悲伤是躲不过的
You can't hidefrom misery.
不关你的事
This isn't your business.
为了救她我的脑壳都开过了
My skull was crackedabcopentrying to save her!
那我们都需要谈心和同情
Then we all needaabclittle tea and sympathy.
我不想和你再说下去了
I'm throughdiscussing it.
有个病人...
Uh, we have a patient.
那病人直肠出血 显然哪儿也去不了
Who's obviouslynot goingabcanywhere with a bloody rectum.
欢迎你回来
Great to have you back.
其实我--
Actually,abcI'm--
其实他准备彻底毁了他的事业
actually, he'sabout to thrust aabctanto into the bellyof his career.
我要离开这家医院了
I'm leaving the hospital.
- 抱歉我没选对时候 但是abc- 你为什么要走
- I'm sorry, this is obviouslyaabcterrible time-- - why are you leaving?
我只是想换个场景
I just need a changeof scenery.
买盆花吧
Buy a plant.
直肠出血 两项妊娠试验阳性
Rectal bleeding,twoabcpositive pregnancy tests.
我们什么也做不了
There's nothing we can do?
你应该让House长大点 学会尊重我的决定
You could ask houseto be aabcgrown-up and respect my decision.
我只尊重值得我尊重的
I respect thingsthat deserve respect.
你的决定abc就像狗狗超人一样不值得尊重
This decision,on the otherabchand, is a dog wearing a cape!
幻觉出现 心脏无反应--
Hallucinations.Heartabcwon't respond--
病人妊娠试验阳性是因为病人怀孕了
the patient tested positivefor pregnancyabcbecause the patient is pregnant.
你是谁
Hey, who are you?
他是House医生 他太有才了abc就不做自我介绍了
This is dr. House. He's tooabcbrilliantfor introductions.
假阳性
False positive.
你忙到连肚里的种都分不清是谁了
You're too busyto be running aabcday care center in your abdomen.
假阳性
False positive.
你应该等到30以后abc再用婴儿来摧残你的愉悦之门
Not to mention you should waittill at least 30 to punishabcthat pleasure portalwith a 7-pound tissue expander.
我37了  我觉得我没怀孕
I'm 37. And I thought I wasn't pregnant.
37了?
37?
真不错
Impressive.
可惜 你这基因传不下去了
Too bad you'renotabcpassing on those genes.
还是假阳性吗
Does that look falseto you?
你找错地儿了
You were lookingin the wrong room.
卵子着床于子宫更常见
It's more common whenabcthe egglands in the oven.
但有时停在了输卵管
Sometimes it winds upinabcthe fallopian tubes.
罕见的病例中 它会着床于输卵管中
In rare cases, it plummetsthroughabcthe plumbing entirely.
用肠道血管供血
It's using herabcintestineas a blood supply.
这可导致直肠出血 所以...
It caused the rectal bleed, and now...
小孩长啊长abc压迫到了她的迷走神经
junior miss steinem'sjunior mustabcbe pressing on her vagus nerve,
导致心律下降
slowing her heart to a crawl.
把小孩从她肚子里揪出来
Yank the fetus.
要是手术她能活下来 她就没事了
She survives theabcsurgery, she'll be fine.
要是她想留着孩子呢
What if she wantsto keep the baby?
她不想
She doesn'T.
那我们就不能多用两秒钟问一下吗
Well, we can't taketwoabcseconds to discuss this?
我是说胎儿可以一直成活 子宫也一样
I mean, fetuseshave been transplantedabcbefore. Whole uteruses too.
摘除一个长在肠壁上的胎儿abc已经十分凶险
Just terminating the fetus when it'sabcgluedto her intestines is high-risk surgery.
别做梦救下小孩
Saving it is a fantasy.
这段话足有三秒钟
That was at leastthree seconds.
她都已经37了 她应该--
She's a 37-year-oldabcwoman who deserves--
是你的就是你的
people getwhat they get.
跟应不应该没关系
It has nothing toabcdowith what they deserve.
跟她的私处也没关系 一切都由基因决定
And this has nothing to dowith her genitalia,abcand everything to dowith your genetics.
你让我去做的化验
You told meto get tested.
我并不知道那会改变你的医学观点abc你所有的观点
I didn't knowit was gonna color your everyabcmedical opinion,every personal opinion.
你不觉得宣判死亡是--
You didn't thinkaabcdeath sentence would--
人都会死!abc你 amber 所有人
people die!You, amber, everyone.
别表现得跟你刚明白似的
Don't act like youjust figured that out.
我给你一个诊断 你不喜欢abc那边就是出口 你可以走人
I gave you a diagnosis. You don'tabclike it, there are exitson every floor.
我很抱歉这么确定的跟你说
I'm sorry to beso definitive about this.
我知道你还在等候新消息abc但我们没有选择的余地
I know you're still absorbingtheabcnews, but we have no choice.
打掉孩子 我确定
Remove the fetus. Absolutely.
我没有男朋友 没有老公
I have no boyfriend,no husband.
我一直跟patty在一起
I'm on the road with pattyall the time.
在哪儿签字
Where do I sign?
觉得这儿舒服一点了吗?
You feel any tendernessback here?
一点也没有
No, not at all.
现在治疗专业运动损伤了?
Treating professionalsportsabcinjuries now?
不 我不是--
No, I'mabcnot--
习惯一下讽刺幽默好不好
familiar with the conceptof sarcasm.
别抓狂 讽刺是新时尚
Don't sweat it,it's new.
你跟wilson谈过吗?
Have you spoken to wilson?
我们会给你做肌电图 马上回来
We'll get you an ekg.abcI'll be right back.
你想让我跟他上床来留住他?
You want me to sleep withabchimto get him to stay?
那我会找双性恋女人去做
I put the bisexual chickon that.
要是你想帮忙的话 那就去说...
If you'd like to sit in,so to speak...
- 我跟他谈过了abc- 你跟他说什么了?
- I spoke to him.abc- What'd you tell him?
什么也没说 倾听
I didn't tell himanything. I listened.
你什么都没做还自我感觉良好？abc你应该告诉他--
So you could feel goodaboutabcdoing nothing.You gotta tell him--
我不是你的使唤丫头abc这是离开你以后最爽的
I am notyour errand girl.Bestabcthingabout leaving you--
你们俩以前是一对?
the two of youused to be together?
在我减掉最后85磅的时候她甩了我
She dumped me when Iabclostthe last 85 pounds.
还说这样我的爱就少了
Said there was less of meto love.
不幸的人各有各的不幸
Grief means differentabcthingsto different people.
但这对你来说什么也不是
Case in point,means very little to you.
不幸就像那个工业城市abc它就在那里 你躲不掉
Grief is newark. Okay, it'sabcthere. You can't avoid it.
你只能捏着你的鼻子abc但愿不会塞车
The idea isto hold your nose,abchope the traffic'snot too bad,
快点跑到曼哈顿abc不要在那里买房子
and get on to manhattanas quicklyabcas possible, not to buy property.
你觉得这就是面对现实?
You think that'sfacing up to things?
逃跑的又不是我
I'm not the onewho's quitting.
那是因为你什么都不曾失去过
'Cause youhaven't lost anything.
但是你失去过 他会听你的
But you have. Listen to you.
你丈夫死的时候你怎么办的
What did you dowhen your husband died?
我找了份新工作然后离开了
I got a new joband I moved.
看你的决定多烂
See how crappythat worked out?
把胎盘从大肠壁上分离下来
Separating the placenta fromabcthe wall of the large intestine.
纱布 吸一下这里出血了
Sponge. Suction. We'veabcgot some bleeding.
血压在下降 心率90
Bp's dropping. 90 systolic.
她出血太多了 止血钳
She's bleeding like hell. Clamp.
血压还在降
Bp's still dropping.
推一支钙剂 快
Amp of calciumhloride, fast!
- 还在降abc- 闭嘴!
- still dropping.abc- Shut up!
挤压她的脾脏
Squeeze her spleen.
我们要挤出更多血小板来帮助止血
We need to forcesome plateletsabcout so her blood clots.
她现在太弱了 脾脏脆弱会挤碎的
She's in weak shape. Spleen'sabcfriable. It could rupture.
她稳定了 已经不再继续出血了
She's stabilizing. Oozing's drying up.
我讨厌家属开放日
I hate visitors day.
切除胎儿
Removing the fetus.
再见
Bye.
你不能让wilson犯这种职业生涯的错误
You have to stop wilsonfromabccommitting career malpractice.
跟他谈谈
Talk to him.
我已经跟他谈过两次了 他都把我赶出来
I already talkedto himabctwice. He threw me out.
嘲笑他羞辱他abc这些都是你的谈话风格
Mocking himand insulting him-- let's see,abcyes,technically those are categoriesof conversation.
对其他医院屏蔽掉他
Block his referencesto other hospitals.
告诉他不能移交病人 除非...
Tell him he can'thandabcoff his cases until--
跟他谈谈 帮他度过悲伤
talk to him.Deal with his grief.
跟他谈谈他都经历了什么
Talk to himabout whatabche's going through.
真是个好主意 我先带他出去喝一杯
That's a brilliant idea.abcI'll take him outfor a beer.
那就能补偿amber在棺材盒里的事实了
That'll make up for theabcfactthat amber's in a pine box.
告诉他宇宙的随机性和混沌性...
That there's randomnessandabcchaos in the universe.
跟他道歉
Tell him you're sorry.
又不是我杀了她
I didn't kill her.
你喝醉了而且--
You wereabcdrunk and--
是啊 要是她老爸从没喝醉过就不会有她
yeah, if her daddyhadn't been drunk,abcshe might neverhave been born.So--
是你半夜给她打的电话
you called her upinabcthe middle of the night.
因为你她才在那辆巴士上
She was on the busbecause of you.
我又没让她出来
I didn't ask herto come out.
又不是我开的巴士
I wasn't driving the bus.
又不是我开的垃圾车撞上了巴士
I wasn't drivingthe garbageabctruck that hit the bus.
又不是我给她开的杀死她的感冒药
And I did not prescribe hertheabcflu meds that killed her.
是我知道 你说的都对 但是...
Yes, I know,that's all true. But...
你就一点都不觉得内疚?
you really don't feelany sense of guilt?
你想留住他abc就让他知道你关心他
You want to keep him, heabcneeds to knowhe's not alone.
让他知道你也不好过
Just tell him you feellike crap.
这毫无意义
It'd be meaningless.
你就找出点意义来
Well, then,find some meaning.
做点什么
And do something.
她现在有神经科的症状了.
She's gota neurological problem.
术后并发症?
Surgical complication?
我想不是 她一直在眨眼
Don't think so. She keeps on blinking.
她的心脏也没有好转
Her heart's not recovering either.
那怀孕只是个巧合?
So the pregnancywas a coincidence.
心率降到39  阿托品已经是最大量了
Pulse is down to 39. She'sabcmaxed out on atropine.
我们安了起搏电线来避免...
We're installinga pacing wire to...
快来人!
Avoid that. We need some help in here!
- 呼house来abc- 已经呼过了
- Page house.abc- Already paged him.
再呼
Page him again.
你的电话
It's for you.
要是我道歉的话 有用吗?
If I told youthat I was sorry,abcwould it change anything?
我不会相信你的
I wouldn't believe you.
如果你相信我的话
If you believe me.
我不能想象有那样的世界
It's hard to imaginesuch a world.
我要回家了...
I'm going home...
直到你同意留在医院里
until you agree to stayat this hospital.
你不能--这是敲诈
You can'tabcbe--that's blackmail.
还代你工作?
And to do your job?
你干嘛不朝自己脑门上开一枪?
Why not hold a gunto your own head?
那你的良心的痛苦会比我头上流的血还多
Your conscience bleedsmoreabcfreely than my head.
短信
Text.
病人心跳骤停
Patient's in cardiac arrest. Ouchy.
- 你愿意因为我伤害一个病人--abc- 如果能把你留下来的话
- You'd jeopardizea patient becauseabcof my-- - if it keeps you here.
你的友谊对我来说比病人重要
Your friendship mattersmoreabcto me than this patient.
我要做我觉得对的事情
I've gotta do what's rightfor me.
而你做你觉得对的事情
You've gotta do what's rightfor you.
是 但我的更容易做
Yeah. But it comes easier for me.
他在哪儿? 他在哪儿?
where is he? Where is he?
汇报
status.
她的心脏已经稳定了
Her heart's stabilized.
我们给她安了起搏导线 但她心脏没什么改善
We have a pacing wirein her, but theabcbradycardiais not getting any better.
House在吓唬我们
House is bluffing.
我给他打了三次电话 他一次都没接abc你准备让我们怎么做?
I called him three times. He's notabcpicking up. What do you want us to do?
做就跟他在这儿一样的事
The same thing you'd doif he was here.
要是他在这儿 我们会问他该怎么做
If he was here, we'dabcbeasking him what to do.
- 常见怀疑是什么?abc- 没有
- What are the usual suspects?abc- There aren't any.
她有过维生素B12缺乏 我们已经纠正了abc还有异位妊娠 我们也已经手术移除了
She had a vitamin deficiency,and we correctedabcit, an ectopic pregnancy,we removed it.
但是她的心脏症状就是好不了abc现在连脑子都有问题了
But her heart problemwon't go away,abcand now something's wrongwith her brain.
我看好你们哟
I have complete confidencein you guys.
谁去找house来救这个病人的命?
Who wants to goservice houseabcso this patient can live?
没他我们也一样做
We can do thiswithout him.
也许手术中有什么意外发生了
Maybe something happenedabcduring the surgery.
手术做的是她的肠子 又不是脑子
The surgery was on herabcbowel,not her brain.
焦虑 中风 tourette综合征都会导致眨眼
Anxiety, stroke, tourette'sabccould all cause eye blinking.
那会导致她心跳加快 而不是减慢
And cause her heart toabcbeatfaster--it's slowing down.
多发性硬化 如果某处的脱髓鞘病变abc导致交感神经对心脏支配的缺失
M.S.If a lesion took outtheabcsympathetic innervation of her heart,
就可以解释心动过缓和眨眼的问题了
it'd explain theabcbradycardia and the blinking.
但没法解释维他命不足或宫外孕
But not the vitamin deficiencyabcor the ectopic pregnancy.
House希望我们给他个统一的说法
House would want a unifying theory.
House现在不在abc那些症状也没了
House is gone,and so are those sptoms.
多发性硬化症可以解释abc她目前的所有症状
M.S.Explains everythingthat'sabcwrong with her right now.
开始给她上干扰素abc治疗多发性硬化症
Start her on interferonfor M.S.
能进来吗？
Mind if I come in?
当然 我能出去吗?
Not at all. You mind if I leave?
我特意叫你别接那个病例abc去跟Wilson好好谈谈
I told you not to take that casespecificallyabcso you could dealwith wilson.
我干活谈心两不误 你觉得呢?
And the two ended updovetailingabcrather nicely, don't you think?
你就是这么对待兄弟之情的?
Is this how you showyour friendship...
让他受良心谴责而惴惴不安?
by bludgeoning himwith guilt?
因为他是我朋友 我知道他吃哪一套
Because he's my friend,Iabcknow what works on him.
我不能让你对病人置之不理
Well, I can't let youwalkabcaway from a patient.
那就开了我吧
Then fire me.
你情愿拿丢掉饭碗abc也不愿说句"对不起"
You're willing to riskyour career, butabcyou're not willingto say you're sorry.
我跟他道过歉了
I told him I'm sorry.
只是他不信
He didn't believe it.
- 那就让他信啊abc- 我都不信
- Well, make him believe it.abc- I don't believe it.
你只是不愿意去相信
You don't want to believe it.
因为一旦你告诉Wilsonabc你对他的真实感受
Because if you tell wilsonhowabcyou actually feel about him,
告诉他你对Amber辞世的感受abc反省你的作为
about what happenedto amber,abcabout your partin what happened,
你怕他仍然摔门而去
and he walksoutabcthe door anyway--
你这辈子都在装酷abc就不能脆弱一次么...
if you make yourselfvulnerable for once inabcyour nerve-deadening,emotionally obliterating--
你跟他一样
you're doing the same thing he is.
都在躲避现实
You're running away.
只不过他没连累手上的病人
Only he's not killingabcanyone in the process.
House医生在哪儿?
Where's dr. House?
他有点不舒服
He's not feeling well.
他觉得我得了多发性硬化症?
Was M.S.His idea?
是我们小组这样认为
We work as a team.
你知道的 通力协作
You know how it is. Collaborative.
有时很难说是谁想出来的
Sometimes it's hard toabctellwhere an idea comes from.
但你们并不是真正的小组
But you're notreally a team.
你们都是替他工作的
You work for him.
而你替Patty工作abc我相信她的许多想法事实上...
And you work for patty.I'm sureabca lot of her ideas are actually--
我不在她身边 她不会有事的
She would be finewithout me.
没了她 我什么也不是
I'd be nothingwithout her.
这说不定正是次机会
Maybe if you just hadthe chance.
我肯定你已经学到了很多
I'm--I'm sureyou'veabclearned a lot.
人人生来并非平等的
Not everybody'screated equal.
House医生觉得我abc是多发性硬化症吗?
Does dr. House thinkI have M.S.?
是的
Yes.
你刚刚是不是打颤了?
Did you just shiver?
你有点发低烧
You're running a slight fever.
是坏消息吗?
Is that bad?
说明不是多发性硬化症
It means we were wrongabout the M.S.
你把我的有线电视给掐了!
You had my cabledionnected!
你反应还真大
Well,that's quite a leap.
因为我正好有个31人的维修部
Just becauseI happen to have aabc31-person maintenance department--
你把他们给得罪了个遍
each of whomyou've personallyabcabused at some point--
为什么?abc我连病人的生死都不以为意
why? Did you think I'mabcokaywith letting someone die,
你以为看不了名人保龄球赛abc我就会折腰?
but I'm gonna fold ifI can'tabcwatch celebrity bowling?
没准你吃的就是这一套
That is notan unreasonable theory.
特别是你最爱的肥皂剧abc十分钟后就要开播了
Especiallywith only tenabcminutes till your favorite soap.
奇怪  这不是医生休息室的遥控器?
Oh, gee, is this theabcremotefrom the doctors' lounge?
你说十万火急就这事? 我走了
this is your 911? Good-bye.
站住!
Stop!
我已经向大纽约地区所有医院abc扣发了你的薪资收入状况
I'm withholdingyour salary history fromabcevery hospitalin the tri-state area.
干得好 小姑娘
You go, girl.
我会永久把楼里的电视频道abc都设为陶艺频道 除非你们坐下来谈谈
And I'm permanently settingevery tv in this buildingabcto the pottery channel unless you both sit down.
欢迎来夫妻咨询
Welcome to couplescounseling.
不是手术的问题
it's not the surgery.
时间符合
The timing fits.
位置不符合abc除非她脑子长在肠子里
The location doesn't, unlessherabcbrains are in her bowels.
如果她的血流受到细菌侵染abc有可能会导致脑部感染
If bacteria enteredher bloodstream, itabccould have causedan infection in her brain.
手术没问题 你在场 亲眼看到的
the surgery went fine.abcYou were there, you saw.
消化链球菌属可以解释眨眼的问题...
Peptostreptococcuscouldabcexplain the blinking and--
不 你想从带杂点的录像带上abc找出神迹
no.You want to watcha grainyabcvideo and have an epiphany.
别吵了
Shut up.
你们让我怀念House的冷嘲热讽了
You're making me misshouse's mocking.
你说过这不关我们的事
I know you told usitabcwas none of our business,
但要是House认为你的亨廷顿舞蹈病abc在影响你的话 也许它真的...
but if house thinks that your huntington'sabcis affecting you, maybe it really--
不是的 因为我没得...
it's not, becauseIabcdon't have--
你这么急迫的想靠自己来诊断
you're desperate to do thiswithout him.
你不是想治好她
You're not trying to cure her.
- 你是想证明...abc- 暂停一下录像带
- You're trying toabcpve-- - stop the tape.
放大
Zoom in.
在吻合处那儿 有个小肿块
On the anastomosis,that little bump.
那是个血肿
It's a hematoma.
是个无害的小血囊abc所以Chase在手术过程中没管它
A harmless pocket of blood, which isabcwhy chase ignored itduring the surgery.
有可能是神经节瘤abcChase没发现它不应该
Could be a ganglioma, which isabcwhy chaseshouldn't have ignored it.
是神经异常生长abc可以引起病人的所有症状
It's an abnormal growth of nerves, itabccould be causingall the patient's symptoms.
我们要再给她开一刀 取一份样本
We have to open her upabcagain. Get a piece of it.
你有什么要对我们说的吗?
So what do you wantto tell us?
没什么好说的 我说什么都无济于事
Nothing. Nothing I sayisabcgonna change anything.
你俩得好好谈谈
You guys need to talk.
事实上 你该读读心理学的文献
Actually, you should justabcreadthe psych literature.
压抑说获得广泛支持
Repression's gaining a lot of fans.
你们逃避的东西不会压垮你们的
What you don't facecan't crush you.
敞开心扉聊聊吧
Talk to each other.
你怎么样? 还好吗?
How you doing? Good?
还好 谢谢
Fine, thanks.
坐下!
Sit!
看看 现在你们就是朋友了
See, the two of you are friends.
- 看看你们俩...abc- 我们都认为你是白痴
- Look how you both--abc- think you're an idiot.
我们还都用叉子吃饭
We both also eatwith forks.
- 那也不能说明...abc- 跟他谈谈!
- That doesn't reallyabcprove-- - talk to him!
告诉他你对他是怎么想的
Tell him how youabcfeelabout what he's doing.
我跟他说了 说他是个白痴
I told him he's an idiot.
告诉他关于他要辞职abc你是怎么想的
Tell him what youabcthinkabout him leaving.
- 我觉得他是个白痴abc- 你是个白痴 他很痛苦
- I think he's an idiot.abc- You're an idiot. He's in pain.
你的所作所为abc就是勒索他的良心
And your response is justtoabcemotionally blackmail him.
你跟我说过你在这点上的看法了
You told me what yourabcpositionis on that one.
你是不支持我这么做的 是吧?
You're against it, right?
她没当着我面跟你说过
She hasn't told youin front of me.
她需要证明她是站在我这边的
She needs to proveshe's on my side.
去死吧
Go to hell.
那套理论不管用了
So much for that theory.
你失去了Amber我很遗憾
I'm sorry you lost amber.
我无法想象你经历了什么
I cannot imagine what itabcis you're going through.
但把关心你的人抛开abc也不会让你好起来的
But it will not get betterby you walkingabcaway from everyone that cares about you.
你认为Amber会希望你抽身离去吗?
Do you think amberwouldabcwant you to walk away?
医院里根本没人喜欢Amber
Nobody at this hospitaleven liked amber.
下周同一时间?
Same time next week?
第一次大手术中差点挂掉的病人abc你们想让我再给她动第二次大手术
You want me to doa second major surgery on aabcpatient we almost lostduring a first major surgery
去看看她是否需要动第三次大手术?
to see if she needsaabcthird major surgery?
我们需要一份神经节瘤的样本
We need a pieceof the ganglioma.
你们说的是别的病人吧
Then you're talkingaboutabcanother patient.
你们的病人没有神经节瘤
Yours doesn't havea ganglioma.
要是她有一个 你又没发现呢?
And if there is oneand you missed it?
那么你们说的是别人的手术吧
Then you're talkingaboutabcanother surgeon.
我什么也没漏掉
I didn't miss anything.
我们说的不是别人的手术录像
But we're not talkingaboutabcanother videotape.
这盘录像上显示有一个血肿abc我们要做个活组织切片检查
This one showed aabcbump. We need to biopsy.
有个血肿? 是的abc我祖父就是死于一个血肿
A bump? Oh, yeah. Myabcgrandfather diedof a bump.
再来一次全麻她受不起的abc更别说去做第三次手术了
She can't survive a second roundofabcgeneral anesthesia, let alone a third.
- 你是为了House这样做的abc- 对
- You'd do this for house.abc- Yeah.
你的建议是?
Then what do you suggest?
因为病人发高烧 心率偏低
Because the patient's got aabchigh fever, a low heart rate,
我们像这样傻站着的话abc她存活的几率几乎没有
and a dim chance of survivalifabcwe stand here like idiots.
我的建议是 你们别这样傻站着
Then I suggest youabcdon'tstand there like idiots.
怎么把煤从别人山头上弄下来?
How do you get coalout of a mountainabcwhen it's someone else'smountain?
House不在 不意味着我们不能abc像House那样思考问题
If we don't have house,it doesn'tabcmean we can't think like house.
但我们不用非得像他那样说话
But it does mean we don'tabchaveto talk like him.
不是直接往下挖abc而是从边上开始挖
You don't dig down.abcYou go in from the side.
从直肠插一根有光内窥镜进去abc移动肠道 直至我们找到神经节瘤
We insert a lighted scopethrough the rectum,abcmove the intestine tillwe find the ganglioma,
然后把它推至表面
then push it to the surface.
朝光源那儿切个口子
Where we see the light,we cut.
我们会切个尽可能小的口子
We'll make as smallabcan incisionas we can.
但不幸的是 会非常痛
But unfortunately,it'll be very painful.
你刚经历过一次手术abc我们不能给你上麻药
After your surgery experience,weabccan't give you anesthesia.
能跟House医生谈谈吗?
Can I talk to dr. House?
不 我们可以的abc我们知道自己在做什么
No. We can do this. Weabcknow what we're doing.
并非有意冒犯 但我的前任老板abc并不主张我到这儿来 因为你们或...
I don't mean to beinsulting, but my former bossabcdidn't insiston me coming here because of you or--
你前任老板?
your former boss?
她又找到人了
I've been replaced.
- 我很抱歉 你肯定...abc- 我没事
- I'm sorry.Youabcmust be-- - I'm fine.
她去北京有要事 有一堆要烦的事
She has a big beijingabctrip. Ton of work to do.
她没空去等我康复
She can't just wait for meto get better.
我们都受过良好训练
We've been well-trained.
会照顾好你的
We'll take good care of you.
你怎么能让她对你像个踏脚凳一样?
How can you let herabctreat youlike a footstool?
这世界需要仆役
The world needs flunkies.
别这么说 你不是仆役
Don't say that. You're better than that.
我觉得这么说没什么不可abc你为什么有意见?
I have no problem with it. Why do you?
因为... 人生苦短
Because... life is short.
你有可能死在手术台上
I mean, yours could'veabcendedin that surgery.
你从来没为自己活过
You'd have never livedfor yourself.
这是哪门子女权主义...abc我们可以拥有一切
What kind of feminist--weabccan have anything.
不 我们不能 我们可以渴求一切
No, we can'T. We can aspire to anything.
但我们不能因为自己想要abc而就能拥有一切
But we don't get itjustabcbecause we want it.
我宁可生活与鸟为伍abc也不愿浪费时间希望自己能有翅膀
I would ratherspend my life close to theabcbirds than waste itwishing I had wings.
通过了乙状结肠 进入降结肠
you're through the sigmoid,abcinto the descending colon.
打开光源
Switching on the light.
向前直至吻合处
Advance towardthe anastomosis.
就是这儿
That's it.
将肠壁向肚皮推
Push the wall of theabcintestine toward the skin.
好了 我看到了
There, I see it.
别往下看
Don't look down.
手术刀
Scalpel.
你周五干完就要走了
So your last dayis friday.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
你不该走
You shouldn't go.
是不是House让你跟我说的 还是abc你想救那个病人? 因为我横竖都...
Did house ask youto talk to me, or are you tryingabcto savethe patient?Because there'll always be--
- House跟我说过abc- 你答应他了
- house asked me.abc- And you're doing it.
我叫他去死
I told him to go to hell.
谢了
Thanks.
不过我觉得他是对的
But I think he's right.
你以为你的选择很理性
You think you'reabcmakinga rational choice.
你以为最坏的都过去了 然后...
You think the worstis over. And then...
半年后 你回过头看看abc意识到你不知道自己做了什么
six months lateryou look back and youabcrealize you didn't knowwhat you were doing.
你是说痛苦不会消散?
Are you saying the paindoesn't go away?
会轻些 或许两个月后abc或许两年后
It gets easier. Not in twoabcmonths. Not in two years.
但是没错abc痛苦不会真正消散
But no, it never reallygoes away.
在这儿 这楼里 我待在休息室里
Being here--this building--abcI was just in the lounge.
一直盯着Amber的储物柜看
I kept staringat amber's locker.
今早看到一个披着头巾的人
I saw a guy wearing a scarfthis morning.
那颜色让我想起了他的眼睛
The color reminded meof his eyes.
我们的家离这里有500英里
We lived 500 milesfrom here.
我要做点什么
I have to do something.
那就去做
Then do it.
但别认为那是正确的选择 因为...
But don't thinkit's theabcright choice, because...
没有什么正确的选择
there isn't one.
这不是神经节瘤
it's not a ganglioma.
不是手术的问题
The problemwasn't the surgery.
异常沉积的蛋白质
Abnormally depositedproteins.
是淀粉样变性 可以解释眨眼以及abc心率过缓的原因
It's amyloidosis. That would explainabcthe blinkingand the low heart rate.
治疗淀粉样变性的唯一方法abc就是治疗引发此病的一切原因
Only way to treatamyloidosis isabcto treatwhatever's causing it.
引起淀粉状蛋白的东西没有太多
It's not as if a lotabcof thingscause amyloid.
风湿性关节炎
Rheumatoid arthritis.
家族性地中海热
Familial mediterranean fever.
淋巴瘤
Lymphoma.
我们不可能都是对的
Well, we can't allbe right.
但可能都是错的
But you can allbe wrong.
病人关节不痛
The patient's joints don't hurt,
移除胎儿后腹痛消失abc无可触淋巴结
abdominal pain went awaywhen theabcfetus did, and no palpable lymph nodes.
能说些有建设性的吗?
Got anything constructiveto say?
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
她有很多可触淋巴结abc关节和腹部疼痛
Um, she has lots and lotsof palpableabclymph nodes, joint and abdominal pain.
晚饭时就能治好啦
She'll be better by dinnertime.
要是找不到淀粉样变性病的起因
If we don't find theabccauseof the amyloidosis,
她就无法摘掉起搏导线abc永远走不出医院了
we never get her offthat wire, sheabcnever walks outof this hospital.
谁需要house呢?
But hey,who needs house, hmm?
丢掉学步车的感觉真好
So glad we lostthose training wheels.
你想让我做主?
You want me to makethe call?
大家意见不一
There seems to besome disagreement.
不是强留我的借口?
And this isn't justa pretextabcto pressure meinto staying?
看上去像借口?
Does it look likea pretext?
不像
No.
她真的快不行了
She really is dying,isn't she?
发炎 核仁扩大 有丝分裂像
Inflammation,enlargedabcnuclei, some mitotic activity.
可能是淋巴瘤
It could be lymphoma.
没有可触淋巴结
There areno palpable lymph nodes.
这点只降低可能性 没能把它排除
It makes it less likely,abcbut it doesn'trule it out.
我是个肿瘤专家 觉得是肿瘤
I'm an oncologist. I see cancer.
给免疫专家看 会觉得是免疫疾病
Show it to an immunologist,abcthey'll see autoimmune.
已经给免疫专家看过了
I already showed itto an immunologist.
开始化疗吧
We'll start her on chemo.
你应该走
You should leave.
House不想失去伙伴
House doesn't want to losehis sidekick.
Cuddy不想失去照看house的人
Cuddy doesn't want toabcloseher check on house.
没人关心你的需要
No one's talkingabout what you want.
重点不是我的需要
It's not that I want to.
需要也好 必要也好
Want to, need to.
如果离开这能使生活好过哪怕一点点abc就去吧
If there's any chancethat being away from hereabcwill make your lifeeven a little bit easier, do it.
在这的任何人都会这么做的
That's what everyone else herewould do.
别期待很快好起来
Don't expect anythingto change too fast.
淋巴瘤是你的主意?
Lymphoma was your idea?
怎么?
Why?
我感觉好点了
I feel better.
有时候心理暗示会有帮助
Sometimes just knowingyou'reabcbeing treated helps.
你们试了18种疗法
You've given me18 different treatments.
这是第一次让我感觉好点
This is the first onethatabcmade me feel better.
我不认为这是心理暗示
I don't thinkit's psychological.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该对你发火
I shouldn't havegotten angry at you.
你有自己的选择
Your choices areyour choices.
你跟我不一样
You're not like me.
也许你自己就有翅膀
Maybe you have wings.
我患有亨廷顿舞蹈病
I have huntington's chorea.
十多年左右
Dozen years or so,
我的神经系统 认知能力abc甚至情绪平衡...
my nervous system,my cognitiveabcskills, even my emotional balance...
都会变差
they'll all start to fray.
我不能飞
I won't be able to fly.
不能走路
I won't be able to walk.
不能呼吸
I won't be able to breathe.
你想让你的人生有用
And you want to makeabcsureyour life matters.
我不想只是...
I don't want to just...
按部就班地做事
be tightening boltsandabcfollowing instructions.
我想有些什么...
I want something...
因我而改变
to be different because of me.
我就是
I am.
不只因为你救了我的命
Not just 'causeyou saved my life.
我正申请着一份基金会的工作
I'm applying for a jobat a foundation.
负责财经决策
Running the finance division.
我不知道是否能成 即使不成...
I mean, I don't knowif I'mabcgonna get it, but if I don'T...
也还有别的基金会啊
there are other foundations.
快4点了
it's almost 4:00.
连续剧时间
Soap time.
护士的遥控器
Nurses' remote.
在医生休息室一样能用
Works in the doctors' lounge.
你觉得Wilson为什么要走?
Why do you thinkwilson's leaving?
我还要说"白痴"多少次?
How many times do I havetoabcuse the word "idiot"?
你很满意这个答案?
And that's a good enough answerfor you?
每次有人出现反常
Whenever anyone doesabcanythingout of the norm,
你总是认为人家脑子出问题
you have to tell themwhat screwed-upabcprocess is really at workin their head.
所以我才把你俩关在一起
That is why I lockedtheabctwo of you in a room.
这样你会说些愚蠢刻薄的话abc也许有那么一点真心话
So you would say somethingstupid andabcinsensitive, and maybewith a little bit of truth.
但你却没有
But you didn'T.
我只能认为你不想知道原因
So I can only assume thatabcyoudon't want to know the reason.
你害怕得知真相
You're afraid to know.
你没在听我说话?
You're not listening to me,are you?
自己试试就知道了
Try it sometime. You'll see why.
你看上去像37岁
You look 37.
我是37岁啊
I am 37.
上星期你看上去像27岁
You looked 27 last week.
除非我昏迷了10年 你的皮肤...
Unless I blacked outforabcten years.Your skin--
她有淋巴瘤 也许化疗使她...
she's got lymphoma.Theabcchemo's probably--
停止化疗
stop the chemo.
她感觉好点了 心博徐缓改善了abc我们不需要--
She's getting better. Bradycardia'sabcimproving.We didn't need--
她有瘀伤吗?
she have bruising?
出现幻觉的时她击打过腿
She was pounding herabclegsduring the hallucinations.
不是淋巴瘤
It's not lymphoma.
不要--abc不 不 不
Hey, don't--abcno, no, no.
是我不好  以为你在半推半就
My bad. Thought no meant yes.
这不是瘀伤 是细菌性损害
Those aren't bruises.abcThey're mycobacterial lesions.
她患有扩散性瘤型麻风
She has diffuselepromatous leprosy.
肯定是某次境外刺激之旅时染上的
Must have caught it on one ofabcher overseas estrogen tours.
化疗杀死了部分细菌 她就感觉好些了
Chemo wipes out some of theabcbacteria, she feels a little better.
要是杀死了大部分免疫细胞abc她就会变得更糟
Wipes out mostof her immuneabcsystem, she gets a whole lot worse.
麻风病? 会断掉手脚那种病?
Leprosy? Like where my limbsfall off?
事实上 这种要讨人喜欢些
Actually, this isthe flattering one.
称之为"漂亮麻风"
It's also knownas "pretty leprosy."
不会让人变丑 反而会使皮肤更年轻光滑
It doesn't disfigure, it makesabcyour skin look younger, smoother.
别让女孩们听见
Don't let the girls hear.
否则就都跑来舔你的脸了
They'll all want to lick your face.
不过如果你是女同就无所谓
Unless you're that kindof feminist.
给她用抗生素和强的松 就会好了
Blast her with antibioticsandabcprednisone. She'll be fine.
可恶 过了4点 晚了
Damn, it's after 4:00. I'm late.
- 可恶abc- 什么?
- Damn.abc- What?
她很高兴你能好起来
She's happyyou're gonna be fine.
但是你要是在5分钟前好起来她更高兴
But she'd be happierif you wereabcgonna be fine five minutes ago.
检查结果证实了House医生的诊断
Tests confirmeddr. House's diagnosis.
谢谢老天
Thank god.
你怀孕时 压力触发麻风结节性红斑
When you got pregnant, the physicalabcstress triggeredE. Nodosum leprosum.
一种常见的麻风病并发症
A common complicationof leprosy.
使心脏神经发炎
Inflamed the nervesto your heart.
使其无法吸收维他命 损伤输卵管
Made it hardto absorb vitamins,abcscarred your fallopian tubes.
解释了所有症状
It explains everything.
最好再给我开点润肤乳
Better prescribe mesomeabcskin cream too, huh?
想面试过关还是得用点啊
You might want itforabcthose job interviews.
我要回到Patty身边 替我的人不干了
I'm going back on the roadwithabcpatty. My replacement flamed out.
她说我可以负责些项目abc给我更重要的工作
She says I can managesome projectsabcon my own, carve out more of a role.
你真的认为她会变?
Do you really thinkshe can change?
我不知道 事实上 我不确定--
I don't know.The truthabcis,I'm not sure I--
你可以改变
you can change.
不是...
No...
我不确定我是否想她改变
I'm not sureI want her to change.
她通情达理 只是个老板 而我...
She's reasonable. She's justabcanother employer,and I'm just...
只是其中一个员工而已
another employee.
在某种奇怪的层面 我也有用
In a weird way, I matter.
比起等死我更喜欢你现在这样
I like you betternow that you're dying.
但我弄错了
I was wrong.
你起码试过了
You took a shot.
她打算回去为那混蛋工作
She's going back to workfor that idiot.
真可悲
It's pathetic.
你以为有事会改变?
You thought somethingwould change?
为这工作 她差点没命 我以为--
She almost diedbecause ofabcthat job.Yeah, I--I thought--
差点没命不会改变什么
almost dying changes nothing.
没命却会改变一切
Dying changes everything.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道我不是有意要害她
I know i didn't try to kill her.
我也不想让她受苦
I know ididn't want her hurt.
我知道这都是因为那场该死的车祸
I know it wasa freak accident.
但我感觉糟透了 她因我而死
But I feel like crap,andabcshe's dead because of me.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我想这么做 我也试过
I wanted to. I tried to.
我反复看Amber的病例成百遍abc只想找个怪你的理由
I must have reviewedamber's caseabcfile 100 times to find a way.
但这不是你的错
But it wasn't your fault.
那我们和好了?
Then we're okay?
我知道你不是 但...
I mean, I know you're not, but...
也许我能帮忙
maybe I can help.
我们没和好
We're not okay.
我不是因为Amber的事才离开的
Amber was never the reasonI was leaving.
我不想跟你说是因为--
I didn't want toabctell you because--
我只是想像我常做的那样保护你
because I was trying,likeabcI always do, to protect you.
而这正是问题所在
Which is the problem.
你传播不幸是因为你感觉不到其他感情
You spread misery becauseyouabccan't feel anything else.
你操纵人们是因为你无法处理真正的感情
You manipulate people because you can'tabchandle any kind of real relationship.
而我这些年都纵容你
And I've enabled it. For years.
游戏 胡闹 午夜来电
The games, the binges, theabcmiddle-of-the-nightphone calls.
我才是该在公车上的人 而不是--
I should have been theabconeon the bus, not--
你该一个人去坐公车
you should have en aloneon the bus.
如果我在Amber身上学到什么东西abc那就是人必须照顾自己
If I've learned anythingfrom amber,abcit's that I have to take careof myself.
我们不再是朋友了House
We're not friendsanymore, house.
我都不知道我们原来算不算
I'm not sure we ever were.